Guide to the Arena Stage Collection
Copyright George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Arena Stage Collection: Production Notebooks and Programs
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
vifgm00030
138 containers comprising 46 cubic feet (69 linear feet)
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open to research.
Biographical/Historical Information
Co-founded in 1950 by Zelda Fichandler, Thomas C. Fichandler, and Edward Mangum, Arena Stage was an early leader in the resident theater movement. Mangum, a teacher from George Washington University, and Zelda Fichandler, one of his students, opened the theater in Washington D.C. to fill the void left by the closing of the National Theater in 1948. Donated to George Mason University in fall of 2000, the Arena Stage Collection contains materials that span the theater's more than 50-year history including production notebooks, photographs, playbills, scrapbooks, and handwritten correspondence.
Scope and Content Information
Production notebooks and Programs for Arena Stage productions from 1950 to 1990. Notebooks contain playscripts, music and light cues, wardrobe, prop, notes, and stage-related information.
Arrangement
Alphbetical by production title
Contents List
- Arena Stage Collection: Production Notebooks and Programs
  - Abyssinia (Box Box 1)
  - Accidental Death (Box Box 1)
  - Adding Machine- A Play in Seven Scenes (Box Box 1)
  - The Affair- Prompt Script (Box Box 1)
  - Safety and Accident Reports- Anarchist (Box Box 1)
  - Anarchist- Rehearsal Schedule (Box Box 1)
  - Anarchist- Prelim Plots (Box Box 1)
  - After the Fall- Hong Kong (Box Box 2)
  - After the Fall- Arena (Box Box 2)
  - Ah, Wilderness! (Box Box 3)
  - Alice in Wonderland (Box Box 3)
  - All the King's Men (Box Box 3)
  - All the King's Men (Box Box 4)
  - All The Way Home (Box Box 4)
  - American Buffalo (Box Box 4)
  - The American Dream (Box Box 5)
  - American Splendor (Box Box 5)
  - An American Tragedy (Box Box 5)
  - An American Tragedy (Box Box 6)
  - The Andersonville Trial (Box Box 7)
  - Animal Crackers (Box Box 7)
  - Animal Crackers (Box Box 8)
  - Answered The Flute (Box Box 8)
  - Answered The Flute (Box Box 9)
  - Apollo of Bellac (Box Box 9)
  - Arms and the Man (Box Box 9)
  - The Ascent of Mount Fuji (Box Box 10)
  - As You Like It (Box Box 11)
  - The Autumn Garden (Box Box 11)
  - Awake and Sing! (Box Box 12)
  - Banjo Dancing (Box Box 12)
  - Battle Dream (Box Box 12)
  - Battle Dream (Box Box 13)
  - Bedtime Story (Box Box 13)
  - Beehive (Box Box 13)
  - Beyond Therapy (Box Box 14)
  - Billy Bishop Goes to War (Box Box 14)
  - Blood Knot (Box Box 14)
  - Boccaccio (Box Box 15)
  - Boy Meets Girl (Box Box 15)
  - Briar Patch (Box Box 16)
  - Brother Rat (Box Box 16)
  - The Browning Version (Box Box 16)
  - The Burning of the Lepers (Box Box 16)
  - Buried Child (Box Box 17)
  - Busy Dyin' (Box Box 17)
  - Cabrona (Box Box 17)
  - The Cage (Box Box 18)
  - Candide (Box Box 18)
  - Casualties (Box Box 19)
  - Catsplay (Box Box 19)
  - The Caucasian Chalk Circle- 1961 (Box Box 20)
  - The Caucasian Chalk Circle- 1977 (Box Box 20)
  - The Caucasian Chalk Circle- 1977 (Box Box 21)
  - Checkmates (Box Box 22)
  - The Chemmy Circle (Box Box 22)
  - The Cherry Orchard- 1960 (Box Box 22)
  - The Cherry Orchard- 1970 (Box Box 6)
  - The Cherry Orchard- 1970 (Box Box 23)
  - The Cherry Orchard- 1988 (Box Box 23)
  - The Child (Box Box 23)
  - A Chorus of Disapproval (Box Box 24)
  - Clandestine on the Morning Line (Box Box 25)
  - Cloud 9 (Box Box 25)
  - The Cocoanuts (Box Box 26)
  - Cold Storage (Box Box 26)
  - Comedians (Box Box 27)
  - Conflict of Interest (Box Box 27)
  - The Conquest of the South Pole (Box Box 28)
  - The Country Wife (Box Box 28)
  - The Cretan Woman (Box Box 28)
  - Crime and Punishment (Box Box 28)
  - Crime and Punishment (Box Box 29)
  - The Crucible- 1967 (Box Box 29)
  - The Crucible- 1987 (Box Box 29)
  - The Crucible- 1987 (Box Box 30)
  - The Curse of the Starving Class (Box Box 30)
  - Cymbeline (Box Box 30)
  - The Dance of Death (Box Box 30)
  - The Dance of Death (Box Box 31)
  - Dandelion Wine (Box Box 31)
  - Dark of the Moon- 1948 (Box Box 31)
  - Dark of the Moon- 1964 (Box Box 32)
  - Death of a Salesman (Box Box 32)
  - The Delectable Judge (Box Box 33)
  - The Desert Dwellers (Box Box 33)
  - Design for Living (Box Box 34)
  - Desire Under The Elms (Box Box 34)
  - The Devils (Box Box 34)
  - The Devils (Box Box 35)
  - The Devil's Disciple (Box Box 35)
  - Disability- 1978 (Box Box 35)
  - Disability- 1981 (Box Box 35)
  - Disability- 1981 (Box Box 36)
  - The Disenchanted (Box Box 36)
  - The Doctor's Dilemma (Box Box 36)
  - Don Juan (Box Box 36)
  - Dream Girl (Box Box 37)
  - Duck Hunting (Box Box 37)
  - The Dybbuk (Box Box 38)
  - Edith Stein (Box Box 38)
  - Edith Stein (Box Box 39)
  - Edith Stein (Box Box 40)
  - The Egg (Box Box 40)
  - Emigres (Box Box 40)
  - Enchanted Night - The Police (Box Box 40)
  - Enemies (Box Box 41)
  - Enemy of the People (Box Box 41)
  - Enrico IV- 1964 (Box Box 42)
  - Enrico IV- 1988 (Box Box 42)
  - Enrico IV- 1988 (Box Box 43)
  - Epitaph for George Dillon (Box Box 43)
  - Execution of Justice (Box Box 43)
  - Exhibition (Box Box 44)
  - The Firebrand (Box Box 44)
  - Forever Yours, Marie-Lou (Box Box 44)
  - The Foursome (Box Box 44)
  - The Front Page- 1958 (Box Box 45)
  - The Front Page- 1974-75 (Box Box 45)
  - The Front Page- 1975-76 (Box Box 45)
  - Galileo- 1964-65 (Box Box 45)
  - Galileo- 1964-65 (Box Box 46)
  - Galileo- 1980 (Box Box 46)
  - The Gang's All Here (Box Box 47)
  - Gemini (Box Box 47)
  - Geniuses (Box Box 47)
  - The Girl on the Via Flamina (Box Box 47)
  - Glengarry Glen Ross (Box Box 48)
  - God Bless You, Mr. Rosewater (Box Box 48)
  - Golden Boy (Box Box 49)
  - Good Person of Setzuan (Box Box 49)
  - The Gospel at Colonus (Box Box 49)
  - The Great White Hope (Box Box 50)
  - Hamlet (Box Box 51)
  - Happy End (Box Box 51)
  - Hard Travelin' (Box Box 51)
  - The Hasty Heart (Box Box 52)
  - Heartbreak House- 1976 (Box Box 52)
  - Heartbreak House- 1987 (Box Box 52)
  - A History of the American Film (Box Box 53)
  - A History of the American Film (Box Box 54)
  - Horatio (Box Box 54)
  - The Hostage- 1963 (Box Box 54)
  - The Hostage- 1963 (Box Box 55)
  - The Hostage- 1972 (Box Box 55)
  - Hotel Paradiso (Box Box 56)
  - The House of Blue Leaves (Box Box 56)
  - I'm a Woman (Box Box 56)
  - The Iceman Cometh- 1960 (Box Box 56)
  - The Iceman Cometh- 1968 (Box Box 57)
  - Idiot's Delight (Box Box 57)
  - The Imaginary Invalid (Box Box 57)
  - The Immigrant (Box Box 58)
  - The Importance of Being Earnest (Box Box 58)
  - Indians (Box Box 58)
  - Indians (Box Box 59)
  - Inherit the Wind (Box Box 59)
  - Inherit the Wind (Box Box 60)
  - The Inspector General- 1951 (Box Box 60)
  - The Inspector General- 1967 (Box Box 60)
  - The Inspector General- 1967 (Box Box 61)
  - The Island- Sizwe Bansi is Dead (Box Box 61)
  - Isn't it Romantic? (Box Box 61)
  - Joe Turner's Come and Gone (Box Box 61)
  - Jacques Brel is Alive and Well and Living in Paris (Box Box 62)
  - Judevine (Box Box 62)
  - Julius Caesar- 1951 (Box Box 62)
  - Julius Caesar- 1974-75 (Box Box 62)
  - Julius Caesar- 1974-75 (Box Box 63)
  - Juno and the Peacock- 1958 (Box Box 63)
  - Juno and the Peacock- 1990 (Box Box 63)
  - Kean (Box Box 63)
  - King Lear (Box Box 64)
  - K2 (Box Box 64)
  - Ladder to the Moon (Box Box 64)
  - The Lady's not for Burning (Box Box 64)
  - The Last Meeting of the Knights of the White Magnolia (Box Box 65)
  - Leonce and Lena (Box Box 65)
  - Les Blancs (Box Box 65)
  - The Lesson (Box Box 66)
  - A Lesson From Aloes (Box Box 66)
  - A Lie of the Mind (Box Box 66)
  - Light up the Sky (Box Box 67)
  - Living at Home (Box Box 67)
  - Living at Home (Box Box 68)
  - The Lonesome Train (Box Box 68)
  - A Long Day's Journey Into Night- 1965 (Box Box 68)
  - Long Day's Journey Into Night- 1975 (Box Box 69)
  - A Look at the Fifties (Box Box 69)
  - A Look at the Fifties (Box Box 70)
  - Look Back in Anger (Box Box 70)
  - Loose Ends (Box Box 70)
  - Loose Ends (Box Box 71)
  - The Lower Depths (Box Box 71)
  - Macbeth (Box Box 71)
  - Mademoiselle Colombe (Box Box 72)
  - Madmen (Box Box 72)
  - Madmen (Box Box 73)
  - The Madwoman of Chaillot (Box Box 73)
  - The Magistrate (Box Box 73)
  - Major Barbara- 1959-60 (Box Box 73)
  - Major Barbara- 1967 (Box Box 74)
  - Major Barbara- 1981 (Box Box 74)
  - Man and Superman- 1961 (Box Box 75)
  - Man and Superman- 1985 (Box Box 75)
  - Man of Destiny (Box Box 75)
  - The Man Who Came to Dinner (Box Box 76)
  - The Marriage of Bette and Boo (Box Box 76)
  - Measure for Measure (Box Box 77)
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream- 1982 (Box Box 78)
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream- 1989 (Box Box 78)
  - Merrily We Roll Along (Box Box 78)
  - Merrily We Roll Along (Box Box 79)
  - The Miser (Box Box 79)
  - Moon Children (Box Box 80)
  - The Moon in the Yellow River (Box Box 80)
  - A Month in the Country (Box Box 80)
  - Mother Courage (Box Box 81)
  - The Mousetrap (Box Box 81)
  - Mr. Arcularis (Box Box 81)
  - Mr. Welk and Jersey Jim (Box Box 81)
  - The National Health (Box Box 82)
  - Newis Mountain Dew (Box Box 82)
  - Alexis, We Love You- Recycled (Box Box 82)
  - Nightclub Cantata (Box Box 83)
  - Night Mother (Box Box 83)
  - The Night Thoreau Spent in Jail (Box Box 83)
  - The Night Thoreau Spent in Jail (Box Box 84)
  - No Place to be Somebody (Box Box 84)
  - The 1940s Radio Hour (Box Box 84)
  - The 1940s Radio Hour (Box Box 85)
  - Nothing Sacred (Box Box 85)
  - Oba Koso (Box Box 85)
  - Of Mile and Men (Box Box 85)
  - Oh! What a Lovely War (Box Box 85)
  - Old Times (Box Box 86)
  - Once Around the Block (Box Box 86)
  - Once In A Lifetime- 1962 (Box box 86)
  - Once In A Lifetime- 1976 (Box Box 86)
  - Once In A Lifetime- 1976 (Box Box 87)
  - One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest (Box Box 87)
  - On The Razzle (Box Box 87)
  - On The Razzle (Box Box 88)
  - On the Town (Box Box 88)
  - On The Way Home (Box Box 89)
  - Optimism (Box Box 89)
  - Othello (Box Box 89)
  - Ourselves Alone (Box Box 89)
  - Our Town- 1973 (Box Box 89)
  - Our Town- 1972 (Box Box 90)
  - Our Town- 1976 (Box Box 90)
  - Pantagleize (Box Box 91)
  - Pantomime (Box Box 91)
  - Passion Play (Box Box 92)
  - The Past (Box Box 92)
  - Persecution and Assassination of Marat/Sade (Box Box 92)
  - The Persecution and Assassination of Marat/ Sade (Box Box 93)
  - Philadelphia Story (Box Box 93)
  - The Piggy Bank (Box Box 93)
  - The Piggy Bank (Box Box 94)
  - Play; That Time; Footfalls (Box Box 94)
  - Playboy of The West Indies (Box Box 94)
  - Plenty (Box Box 94)
  - The Plough And The Stars (Box Box 95)
  - Poor Bitos (Box Box 95)
  - Porch (Box Box 95)
  - The Prisoner (Box Box 96)
  - Project Immortality (Box Box 96)
  - A Public Prosecutor Is Sick Of It All (Box Box 96)
  - A Public Prosecutor Is Sick Of It All (Box Box 97)
  - Pueblo (Box Box 97)
  - Pueblo (Box Box 98)
  - The Purification (Box Box 98)
  - Pygmalion- 1950-51 (Box Box 98)
  - Quartermaine's Terms (Box Box 98)
  - Raisin (Box Box 99)
  - Real Estate (Box Box 99)
  - Red Peppers (Box Box 99)
  - The Rehearsal (Box Box 99)
  - The Resistable Rise of Arturo UI (Box Box 100)
  - The Resistable Rise of Arturo UI (Box Box 101)
  - Restoration (Box Box 101)
  - Ring Round The Moon- 1960 (Box Box 101)
  - Ring Round The Moon- 1988 (Box Box 101)
  - Ring Round The Moon (Box Box 102)
  - The Rivals (Box Box 102)
  - The Rivers and Ravines (Box Box 102)
  - Romeo and Juliet (Box Box 102)
  - Room Service- 1954 (Box Box 102)
  - Room Service- 1968 (Box Box 103)
  - The Ruling Class (Box Box 103)
  - The Ruling Class (Box Box 104)
  - Saint Joan- 1965 (Box Box 104)
  - Saint Joan-1976 (Box Box 104)
  - Saturday, Sunday, Monday (Box Box 104)
  - Saturday, Sunday, Monday (Box Box 105)
  - The Scarecrow (Box Box 105)
  - The School For Scandal (Box Box 105)
  - The School For Wives (Box Box 105)
  - The School For Wives (Box Box 106)
  - Scooding (Box Box 106)
  - Screenplay (Box Box 106)
  - Separations (Box Box 106)
  - Separations (Box Box 107)
  - Sergeant Musgrave's Dance (Box Box 107)
  - Shaw Says (Box Box 107)
  - The Sign in Sidney Brustein's Window (Box Box 107)
  - Silent Night, Lonely Night (Box Box 108)
  - Singers (Box Box 108)
  - The Sing Ling Circus (Box Box 108)
  - Six Characters in Search of an Author- 1961 (Box Box 108)
  - Six Characters in Search of an Author- 1961 (Box Box 109)
  - Six Characters in Search of an Author- 1968 (Box Box 109)
  - Six Characters in Search of an Author- 1988 (Box Box 109)
  - Stand-up Tragedy (Box Box 110)
  - Stargazing (Box Box 110)
  - Starting Here, Starting Now (Box Box 110)
  - Status Quo Vadis (Box Box 111)
  - Still Life (Box Box 111)
  - Stray Dogs (Box Box 111)
  - Streamers (Box Box 111)
  - Streamers (Box Box 112)
  - A Streetcar Named Desire (Box Box 112)
  - The Suicide (Box Box 112)
  - The Suicide (Box Box 113)
  - Tales of the Vienna Woods (Box Box 113)
  - Taming of the Shrew- 1964 (Box Box 113)
  - Taming of the Shrew- 1964 (Box Box 114)
  - Taming of the Shrew- 1986 (Box Box 114)
  - Tartuffe (Box Box 114)
  - Tartuffe (Box Box 115)
  - Teibele and Her Demon (Box Box 115)
  - The Tenth Man (Box Box 116)
  - Three Men on a Horse- 1960 (Box Box 116)
  - Three Men on a Horse- 1974 (Box Box 116)
  - The Threepenny Opera- 1963 (Box Box 116)
  - The Threepenny Opera- 1963 (Box Box 117)
  - The Threepenny Opera- 1969 (Box Box 117)
  - The Three Sisters- 1957 (Box Box 118)
  - The Three Sisters- 1966 (Box Box 118)
  - The Three Sisters- 1984 (Box Box 118)
  - Tiger at the Gates (Box Box 118)
  - The Time of Your Life- 1962 (Box Box 118)
  - Tintypes (Box Box 119)
  - Tom (Box Box 120)
  - Tomfoolery (Box Box 120)
  - Total Recall (Box Box 120)
  - Trappers (Box Box 121)
  - The Tot Family (Box Box 121)
  - The Tot Family (Box Box 122)
  - Tricks (Box Box 122)
  - Tricks (Box Box 123)
  - Twelfth Night- 1951 (Box Box 123)
  - Twelfth Night- 1972 (Box Box 123)
  - Twelve Angry Men (Box Box 124)
  - Uncle Vanya (Box Box 124)
  - Under Milk Wood (Box Box 125)
  - Undiscovered Country (Box Box 125)
  - Uptight (Box Box 125)
  - A View From the Bridge (Box Box 126)
  - Volpone (Box Box 126)
  - Waiting for Godot (Box Box 126)
  - A Walk in the Woods (Box Box 127)
  - The Wall (Box Box 127)
  - The Wall (Box Box 128)
  - What Shall We Tell Caroline? (Box Box 128)
  - What The Babe Said? (Box Box 128)
  - What The Butler Saw? (Box Box 128)
  - Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf? (Box Box 128)
  - Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf? (Box Box 129)
  - The Wild Duck (Box Box 129)
  - The Winter's Tale (Box Box 129)
  - The Winter's Tale (Box Box 130)
  - Wipe-Out Games (Box Box 130)
  - Witness for the Prosecution (Box Box 130)
  - Women and Water (Box Box 130)
  - Women and Water (Box Box 131)
  - The World of Sholom Aleichem (Box Box 131)
  - You Can't Take It With You- 1969 (Box Box 131)
  - You Can't Take It With You- 1979 (Box Box 131)
  - You Can't Take It With You (Hong Kong) (Box Box 132)
  - Zalmen, or the Madness of God (Box Box 132)
  - Zalmen, or the Madness of God (Box Box 133)
  - Arena Stage 1950-61 Season Programs (Box Box 134)
  - Arena Stage 1961-68 Season Programs (Box Box 135)
  - Arena Stage 1968-74 Season Programs (Box Box 136)
  - Arena Stage 1974-81 Season Programs (Box Box 137)
  - Arena Stage 1981- 86 Season Programs (Box Box 138)
  - Arena Stage 1987-91 Season Programs (Box Box 139)